Emma Oatley

Software Engineer

emma.oatley.ie



eoatley



m eoatley



emma@oatley.ie



+447730022354

SUMMARY

Software engineer with a holistic mathematical and software background, prepared to relocate. Coding bootcamp graduate, experienced in building full stack projects and maintaining backend microservices. Interested in effective methods to manage data and real-time events.

EXPERIENCE

SAINSBURY'S TECH | ENGINEER

Feb 2023 - Present | London

- → As a backend engineer, I maintain microservices that make up the retail promotions engine using Scala, Akka, PostgreSQL, Kafka and Apache Airflow.
- → Migrating our microservices off legacy cloud infrastructure to improve security and reduce maintenance costs
- → Completed a 3-day AWS course titled 'Running Containers on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service'
- → Studying functional programming, data structures and algorithms
- → I mentor a team of graduates who are developing a full stack project, to improve their hard and soft skills

SAINSBURY'S TECH | ASSOCIATE ENGINEER

April 2022 - Feb 2023 | London

- → As a full stack engineer, I worked towards mastering retail promotions with Node, React, MongoDB, Kafka, Kafka Connect, TypeScript, Docker and Cypress
- → Implemented a feature to allow a new type of Nectar at Argos promotion to be created
- → Worked with our Data Engineer to develop a data model for complex promotions, and implemented the model in MongoDB
- → Actively took part in and led agile ceremonies such as retro, refinement, stand-up, and sprint review

ACADEMY | FULL STACK CODING BOOTCAMP SCHOLAR

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022 | London

- → Learned techniques in JavaScript such as closures and recursion to solve coding katas
- → Created full-stack apps using React and TypeScript on the front-end, and Node.js, Express and PostgreSQL on the back-end, independently and in groups working in an agile way
- → Implemented automated unit and E2E tests
- → Gave presentations on code, apps, and the journey of data through an app
- → Developed emotional intelligence in leadership skills sessions

WESTMINSTER ACADEMY | MATHS TEACHER

Aug 2019 - Aug 2021 | London

- → Taught engaging lessons which allowed all students to progress
- → Helped students to see the best in themselves via lessons, playground conversations and outdoor trips
- → Innovated by designing mail-merges to routinely provide all parents with quantitative and personalised feedback

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Proficient:

TypeScript • JavaScript

Experienced:

Scala • MongoDB PostgreSQL • Kafka

Java • Shell • HTML

LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORKS

React • Node.js • Akka

TOOLS/PLATFORMS

Git • Docker • Kubernetes • AWS • GitHub Actions

EDUCATION

IMPERIAL COLLEGE

MSCI MATHEMATICS Oct 2014 - Jun 2018 | London Specialised in Algebra and Geometry Grade: 2.1

UNIVERSITY OF CANTER-**BURY WITH IMPERIAL COL-**LEGE

PGCE IN MATHEMATICS WITH QTS Sep 2018 - Jun 2019 Maths Teacher Qualification **Grade: Distinction**

OTHER INTERESTS

HOBBIES

Climbing • hiking • food

LANGUAGES

A1 German • A2 French